我们 是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文!
and Steven!
兜
风
欢迎关注微博@ UUU字幕组 获取最新熟肉信息!
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
presisco
校对
Husky
特效
presisco
压制
我们真的非得拾起每块碎片吗?
Do we really have to get every piece?
没错!
Yes!
放任宝石飞船残骸四处散布非常危险
Having a wrecked gem ship lying around is too dangerous.
我们得尽快收拾碎片--所有的碎片
We've got to take care of it--all of it.
而且我们得开始搜寻橄榄石的逃生仓了
And we'll need to start looking for Peridot's escape pod, too,
如果她真的逃到了地球上的话
assuming she even made it to earth.
我们有很多的工作要完成
We've got lots of work ahead of us.
收到
On it.
喔 这块可有点大
Whoa, that's a big one.
史蒂文?
Steven?
史蒂文!
Steven!
嘿 史蒂文 欢迎回到地球
Hey, Steven. Welcome back to earth.
搞毛? 谁说的?
What? Who told you?
你看起来灵魂出窍了 兄弟
You looked a million miles away, man.
哦
Oh.
对不起 我只是走神了
Sorry. I was zoning out.
我们打算去停车场放松一下
We were about to go chill at a parking lot
逗逗老顽固们
and freak out some squares.
"squares"本意"方形"在俚语中指思维死板陈旧的人
你该跟我们一起去
You should come with.
噢 但我-我对方形没什么意见啊
Oh, but I-I don't really have anything against squares.
我喜欢所有的基本形状
I like all basic shapes.
这就是我说的
That's what I'm talking about.
你的这些反观点
You got that much-needed counter-point
能平衡我们的愤世嫉俗
to our cynical world-view.
你必须要来啊
You have to come.
这样才有正能量嘛
It's good energy flow.
对不起 伙计们
Sorry, guys.
我有很多重要的宝石人工作要做
I've got a lot of important gem work to do.
以后再说吧
Maybe later.
可惜
Bummer.
那么 我们之后见
Well, we'll catch you later, then.
我手上的茧子都生出了茧子
The calluses on my hands have calluses.
劳动者的负担真是沉重啊
The working man's burden is truly a heavy one.
批萨雨
Pizza rain.
但没有批萨云
But no Pizza clouds.
搞--
Wha--
你们在这里做什么?
what are you guys doing here?
还有为什么你们要弄个批萨雨?
And why are you making a Pizza rain?
我只愿看到你的笑容...
I only wanted to see you laughing...
在批萨雨中
In the Pizza rain.
这句话出自什么地方吗?
Is that a reference to something?
"laughing in the Pizza rain"出自歌手Prince的著名歌曲"Purple Rain"
来吧 该出来玩一下了
Come on. It's time to hang out.
你不该在晚上浪啊
You can't hang out at night.
晚上该睡觉的
Night is for dreaming.
夜晚是你自己定义的
Night's whatever you want it to be.
时间是幻觉
Time's an illusion.
你不是已经完成工作了吗?
Aren't you done working for the day?
嗯...对啊 好吧
Mm. Yeah, okay.
我们去浪吧
Let's hang out.
爽
Nice.
但首先我们得将剩下的批萨送到笑脸先生手中
But first we need to deliver the rest of this Pizza to Mr. Smiley.
喔! 拂面的狂风--
Whoo! Wind in your face--
这才是我要的
that's what I'm talkin'about.
深呼吸 史蒂文
Breathe deep, Steven.
这可是自由的味道
This is the smell of freedom.
自由闻起来像辣肠
Freedom smells like pepperoni.
这只是车的味道
That's just the car.
你知道什么食物闻起来绝对不像自由吗?
You know what food definitely doesn't smell like freedom?
鱼肉
Fish.
为什么是鱼肉?
Why fish?
呃哦 又来了
Uh-oh. Here we go.
我只是不知道
I just don't get what's wrong
想当DJ有什么错
with wanting to be a deejay.
但我的继父今天又针对我了 他说...
But my step-dad was all on my case again today, sayin'...
我说 "我不想当渔民"
I'm just like, "I don't want to be a fisherman.
穿着雨衣怎么能锐舞呢 继父"
Everyone knows you can't rave in a raincoat, step-dad."
至少他只是在一件事上烦你
At least he only bugs you about one thing.
我爸爸对我的任何作为都指手画脚
My dad's got to say something about everything I do
因为我是市长的儿子
'cause I'm the mayor's son.
我就说 "我想做什么你可管不着
And I'm like, "you can't tell me what to do.
我可是市长的..."
I'm the mayor's..."
等等
Wait.
得了吧!
Puh-lease!
你们的那些对话简直easy
You're just walking in cake with that talk.
你们有了姐妹才会知道什么叫糟
You guys don't even know what bad is until you have a sister.
我每次都得跟她讲明白
But I don't know why I have to spell it out
我是双胞胎中邪恶的那个 而她是善良的那个
that I'm the evil twin and she's the good one.
别求我帮你完成你的作业
Don't ask me to help you with your homework.
我在金属摇滚演唱会呢
I'm at some metal concert.
清官难断家务事
Family stuff is tricky.
几个月前
A few months back,
我爸爸和水晶战士禁止我看电视
my dad and the gems grounded me from TV.
--真闹心--这真是糟糕--不可能吧!
Bummer. That's the worst. No way!
然后我发现水晶战士是外星起义者
And then I found out that the gems are alien rebels
然后太空中还有其他宝石人
and that there are other gems out in space
想弄死我们 因为她们认为我们是叛徒
that want us dead 'cause they think we're traitors.
她们还试图绑架我
And they tried to take me hostage
因为她们认为我是我妈妈
'cause they think I'm my mom.
而且...或许我算是?
And...Maybe I kinda am?
我希望我能和石榴 紫晶与珍珠谈谈这个问题
I wish I could talk to Garnet, Amethyst, and Pearl about it,
但我认为她们有点责怪我害得母亲消失了
but I think they kinda blame me for my mom not being around.
这有点沉重啊
That's heavy.
我想也是
I guess.
但你看起来总是那么积极
But you always seem so upbeat.
你才是真正的大佬 史蒂文·宇宙
You're a real champ, Steven Universe.
没错 伙计
Yeah, man.
我肯定二话不说转行当渔夫
I'd turn to fishing in a heartbeat
只要能不和那个--那个!
if it meant not dealing with tha--that!
快看!
Look at that!
什么?! 我撞上什么了? 怎么了?!
What?! What did I hit it? What is it?!
在发-----光
Gloooowing.
我们得去看看
We got to check it out.
我支持
I'm down.
好吧 抓紧
All right. Hold on.
简直有六百个荧光棒那么亮
That's as bright as like 600 glow sticks.
橄榄石的逃生舱!
Peridot's escape pod!
好吧 所有人往后站!
Okay, everybody step back!
这是个宝石人机械 可能非常危险
This is a gem machine and could be extremely dangerous.
看我
Check it out.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
喔 停下!
Whoa, stop!
橄榄石可能还在里面!
Peridot might still be in there!
橄榄啥?
Peri-what?
这个东西是空的
This biz is empty.
看起来是坏了
It looks so busted.
你们得远离那里!
You need to get away from there!
你得放松一下
You need to relax.
它又没什么动作
It's not doing anything.
这不仅是逃生舱的事
It's not just the pod.
这意味着橄榄石就在地球上的某处
This means Peridot is just out there somewhere,
试图伤害地球
trying to hurt the earth.
这不酷 地球万岁
Not cool. Earth forever.
石头来也
Here come the rocks.
史蒂文 跟我与这个东西来个合影吧
Steven, come take a selfie with me and this thing.
不 珍妮 我是认真的
No, Jenny, I'm serious.
我也是
So am I.
酸奶油 你呢?
Sour Cream, what about you?
当然 我干啥都行
Sure. I'm down for whatever.
巴克?
Buck?
算了 我享受当下就好
I like to just experience the moment for what it is sometimes.
而且 这儿光照条件不好
Plus, the lighting is weird.
呃 好吧 史蒂文? 最后问你一次
Ugh, okay. Steven? Last call.
我有滑稽的贴纸!
I got funny stickers!
叛逆
女子
这些真是太好了!
These are so good!
我看起来怎么样?
How do I look?
好极了!
You look great!
站着别动
Look, stay right there.
我想再拍一--
I wanna take one mor--
史蒂文 进去吧!
Steven, get in it!
啊?
W-what?
就一下就好! 拍个照
Just for a second! One picture.
好吧 准备
Okay, ready.
三 二...
Three, two...
什么--
Wha--
天辣噜! 史蒂文!
Oh, my gosh, Steven!
蛤? 这真是太酷了!
Wha? This is so cool!
史蒂文!
Steven!
你是怎么做到的?
How are you doing that?
我想它跟随我的手势而动
I think it listens to what my hands do.
我真的不应该玩弄这个
I really shouldn't be playing with this.
我必须得将这个立即带回神庙
I have to take this back to the temple immediately.
别啊 你刚让它正常工作!
No way. You just got it working!
老兄 你不是你的妈妈吗?
Come on, aren't you your own mom?
谁也管不了你NYou can do whatever you want.
是啊 用这玩意转几个圈圈
Yeah, you got to do some donuts in that thing.
至少一打 或者十三个
At least a dozen. Baker's dozen.
说真的 史蒂文 你一直都承受着巨大的压力
Seriously, Steven, you've been under a lot of pressure.
你不认为你该享受点乐趣吗?
Don't you think you deserve to have a little fun?
嘿!
Hey!
你看来掌握了那个东西了?
You really got the hang of that thing, huh?
当然!
Yeah!
它总是向左倾
It always hooks to the left.
不过我真的该把它带回给水晶战士了
I should really get it back to the gems, though.
别啊!
No!
先跳过那个干草堆再说!
Or right after I jump that haystack!
没错! 上吧!
Yeah! Come on! Do it!
毁了它 史蒂文!
Wreck it up, Steven!
我还好
I'm okay.
也没坏得那么严重 只需要轻轻地敲--
It's not actually so bad if you just give it a little--
啊!
Aah!
史蒂文?
Steven?
伙计们?
Guys?
这里史蒂文对呼吸液的反应类似"新世纪福音战士"中的碇真嗣
史蒂文! 发生了什么?
Steven! What's going on?
伙计们 能听到我吗?
Guys, can you hear me?
我就知道! 那个信号弹直接带我们到达了逃生舱!
I knew it! That flare led us right to the escape pod!
这里发生了什么?
What's going on here?
救命! 帮帮我们! 在这!
Help! Help us! Over here!
石榴 紫晶 珍珠!
Garnet, Amethyst, Pearl!
我们会救你们的 人类!
We'll save you, humans!
难以置信! 橄榄石还在里面
I can't believe it. Peridot's still inside.
她很可能因为迫降非常虚弱
She's probably weak from the landing.
毫不留情
Don't hold back.
了解!
Got it!
不!
No!
喔!
Whoa!
你来这里避难真是嚣张啊
You got a lot of nerve taking refuge here,
那么多地方可去!
of all places!
石榴?
Garnet?
但是你居然敢用
But I don't know where you get off
你那渣渣逃生舱攻击毫无防护的人类
attacking defenseless humans in your deadbeat escape pod.
石榴! 是我 史蒂文!
Garnet! It's me, Steven!
能听到我吗? 石榴!
Can you hear me? Garnet!
你如果觉得你在里面很安全 那么 我告诉你
And if you think you're safe here, well, I got news for you.
你输了!
You lost!
现在...
Now...
石榴! 石榴! 石榴!
Garnet! Garnet! Garnet!
...滚出我的星球!
...stay off my planet!
停下!
Stop!
史蒂文在里头
Steven's in there.
噢 史蒂文!
Oh, Steven!
你在里面干吗?!
what were you doing?!
你发现了橄榄石的逃生舱
You found Peridot's escape pod,
而你没有立即呼叫我们?
and you didn't come get us immediately?
兄弟 我们差点废了你
Dude, we almost wrecked you.
史蒂文 这不可接受
Steven, this is unacceptable.
我对你非常失望
I'm very disappointed in you.
你说得对
You're right.
嘿! 别对他这么严肃
Hey! Cut him some slack.
这又不是他的错!
It's not his fault!
让他当DJ又怎么样!
Just let him be a deejay!
啥?
Wha?
我们只是想让史蒂文高兴一下
We just wanted Steven to have some fun.
我不懂这些外星人绑架
I don't know what's going on with aliens
还有他是自己的母亲这些事
trying to abduct him and him being his own mom,
但听上去他心里有很多事情
but it sounds like he's got a lot on his mind.
我知道你们让他做的那些事都很重要
I'm sure whatever you're having him do is important,
但每个人都有需要休息的时候
but everyone needs a break once in a while.
他还只是个孩子
He's just a kid.
哦 也许我们之前是有点太过严格了
Oh, maybe we have been a little hard on him.
他的确才带我们逃出太空监狱
He did just break us out of space jail.
史蒂文
Steven.
你从现在起可以看电视了
You're ungrounded from TV.
我是无敌的!
I'm invincible!
地球万岁!!
若我能开始改变
If I could begin to be
到你期望的一半
Half of what you think of me
我愿付出我的一切
I could do about anything
我甚至能学着去爱
I could even learn how to love
如你
like you